<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-12T14:31:01-07:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tea in SEA</title><subtitle>Just another blog about tea!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Trying out Kroger Pay: Our take on Kroger’s new payment app</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/trying-out-kroger-pay.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trying out Kroger Pay: Our take on Kroger's new payment app" /><published>2020-06-26T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-26T18:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/trying-out-kroger-pay</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/trying-out-kroger-pay.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-kroger-pay&quot;&gt;What is Kroger Pay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kroger pay is a app-based contactless payment method for certain Kroger stores in the US. It generates a one-time use QR code that gets scanned when you check out. It helps customers make payments for their purchase more smoothly. While Kroger stores still don’t accept Apple Pay or Google Pay, select Kroger stores have rolled this out since 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kroger_pay.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-kroger-pay-works&quot;&gt;How Kroger pay works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers first need to download the Kroger Pay app, or an app of a Kroger store, such as QFC. Then, they can link it to a major credit, debit or prepaid card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you install the app and enter your payment info, you can use it as simple as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the Kroger Pay app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter your custom PIN or use FaceID&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scan the presented QR code to complete your purchase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QR code has the added benefit of also automatically communicating your loyalty or rewards card information, so it can help you save more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;benefits-of-using-kroger-pay&quot;&gt;Benefits of using Kroger Pay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contactless payment, which is very important in the times of COVID-19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t have to carry around your wallet or credit cards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skip entering your rewards card info, since it’s automatically done by the app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use virtual prepaid debit cards, which typically can’t be used for physical grocery shopping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fun fact! You might get more credit card rewards through Kroger Pay. For example, the Bank of America Cash Rewards card codes Kroger Pay transactions as Online Shopping, though YMMV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have Kroger pay set up on your phone, it is quick, safe and very convenient.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is Kroger Pay Kroger pay is a app-based contactless payment method for certain Kroger stores in the US. It generates a one-time use QR code that gets scanned when you check out. It helps customers make payments for their purchase more smoothly. While Kroger stores still don’t accept Apple Pay or Google Pay, select Kroger stores have rolled this out since 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Get Dark Sky for free on your home screen</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/get-dark-sky-for-free.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get Dark Sky for free on your home screen" /><published>2020-06-26T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-26T18:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/get-dark-sky-for-free</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/get-dark-sky-for-free.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-dark-sky-for-free-on-your-home-screen&quot;&gt;Get Dark Sky for free on your home screen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dark Sky weather app is the #1 weather app on the iOS app store, but costs $3.99 to download. But there is a way to try it out for free and get it on your home screen. Did you know that while the Dark Sky Weather app costs $3.99, the Dark Sky website is free to use? You can get the same hyperlocal forecasts for free there, as you can in the paid app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dark_sky_app_store.PNG&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-the-dark-sky-website&quot;&gt;Using the Dark Sky website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply enter your city or zip code in the search bar at https://www.darksky.net and you can access the Dark Sky hyperlocal forecast for your location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dark_sky_web.PNG&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-the-dark-sky-shortcut-to-your-ios-home-screen&quot;&gt;Adding the Dark Sky shortcut to your iOS home screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Dark Sky forecast page for your location, simply tap the Safari menu button at the bottom-center and select “Add to Home Screen” to add the Dark Sky website to your home screen. It will look like and behave the same as the paid Dark Sky app, although it lacks the real-time weather notifications that Dark Sky is famous for. But hey it’s almost like you got Dark Sky for free, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dark_sky_home_icon.PNG&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Get Dark Sky for free on your home screen</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Ways to get more food for your money at Chipotle</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/7-ways-to-get-more-food-for-money-chipotle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Ways to get more food for your money at Chipotle" /><published>2020-06-26T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-26T18:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/7-ways-to-get-more-food-for-money-chipotle</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/frugal/2020/06/26/7-ways-to-get-more-food-for-money-chipotle.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-the-burrito-bowl&quot;&gt;Choose the Burrito Bowl&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically everything on the Chipotle menu costs the same, you just pay more or less depending on your meat choice. Statistically, the Burrito Bowl contains the most food. A Chipotle bowl equivalent of a burrito contains almost the same number of calories as the burrito. If you add in a side tortilla and chances are that the bowl will have a higher calorie count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;order-double&quot;&gt;Order double&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know you can customize almost any part of your burrito bowl? (I hope you chose to get that bowl!). Some customizations, such as adding guac or getting extra meat will cost you extra, but other basic customizations are completely free. These include getting double beans, double rice, or extra veges. Just tell the Chipotle Burrito maker something like “May I have double Pinto beans” …Or Try it out yourself on the Chipotle app to see what you can get extra of at no charge. If you choose your customizations right, you can easily get two meals worth of food into one bowl… Which leads me to my next point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eat-half-and-save-half-for-later&quot;&gt;Eat half, and save half for later&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, a normal Chipotle bowl already contains more than enough calories for a typical meal for me. Now, if you customize your meal to maximize the food, you can almost get two meals out of one meal. Now when you eat it, you just have to finish eating half of it, and save half for later. Before you start eating, try to visualize what half the meal looks like, and make sure to stop eating once exactly you reach the point. Perhaps you may feel the temptation to finish the meal, but just throw the rest into the fridge and eat it later for maybe dinner. This way, you can pretty much get two meals out of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;order-vegeterian-get-free-guacamole&quot;&gt;Order vegeterian, get free Guacamole&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing to get no meat (or no sofritas) will get you free Guacamole at Chipotle, either with the meal or on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-your-eye-out-for-chipotle-gift-card-deals&quot;&gt;Keep your eye out for Chipotle Gift Card deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online retailers and local grocery stores offer discounted Chipotle gift cards 3~5 times a year for 15%~20% off. Recently, I was able to snag a $25 gift card for $20 at Kroger, and a $100 gift card for $85. You can keep your eye out on Slickdeals for Chipotle gift cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-the-rewards-program&quot;&gt;Join the rewards program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chipotle has a nice app where you can earn rewards by spending money at Chipotle. As of July 2020, members will receive a free Burrito once they reach 1250 points. You receive a point for every 10 cents you spend, pre-tax, at Chipotle. This means that a typical Chicken Burrito, which runs $7.35 before tax will earn you 73 points. So you’ll need to buy about 17 Burritos to get one free. This rewards program may not be as good as other chains, but it’s free food is better than nothing, right? Also, the Chipotle app occasionally gives your members-only coupons, like free guac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skip-the-coke&quot;&gt;Skip the Coke&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is that cup of Coke unhealthy for you, but it also costs you about $2. Even if you want to drink it, it is almost always cheaper to get a bottle of coke from elsewhere. That’s why I always skip the coke.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Choose the Burrito Bowl Basically everything on the Chipotle menu costs the same, you just pay more or less depending on your meat choice. Statistically, the Burrito Bowl contains the most food. A Chipotle bowl equivalent of a burrito contains almost the same number of calories as the burrito. If you add in a side tortilla and chances are that the bowl will have a higher calorie count.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Bank of America Cash Rewards Credit Card</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/creditcards/2020/04/07/bank-of-america-cash-rewards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bank of America Cash Rewards Credit Card" /><published>2020-04-07T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T18:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/creditcards/2020/04/07/bank-of-america-cash-rewards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/creditcards/2020/04/07/bank-of-america-cash-rewards.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;bank-of-america-cash-rewards-credit-card-review-a-supporting-player-in-your-credit-card-strategy&quot;&gt;Bank of America Cash Rewards Credit Card Review: A Supporting Player in Your Credit Card Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bank of America Cash Rewards is a choose-your-own-adventure rewards credit card that allows you to pick a bonus category each month from a set list. It also offers 15 billing cycles of 0% interest on purchases and balance transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bank_of_america_cash_rewards.png&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-facts&quot;&gt;Quick Facts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No annual fee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$200 cash back bonus after you make at least $1,000 in purchases in the first 90 days of account opening&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Earn 3% cash back in the category of your choice, 2% at grocery stores and wholesale clubs (up to $2,500 in combined choice category/grocery store/wholesale club quarterly purchases) and unlimited 1% on all other purchases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re a Preferred Rewards member, you can earn 25% - 75% more cash back on every purchase depending on your standing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0% Introductory APR for 15 billing cycles for purchases, and for any balance transfers made in the first 60 days. After the intro APR offer ends, 15.49% - 25.49% Variable APR will apply. 3% fee (min $10) applies to all balance transfers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No annual fee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonus cash back offer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High cash back percentage for chosen category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3% foreign transaction fee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-benefits&quot;&gt;Main benefits:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This card is a cash back card, so you won’t see any particular amazing benefits. The main benefit of this card is a comparitively high cash back rate of 3%~5.25% on a category of your choice. Otherwise, this card is similar to many other cards cash-back cards, offering standard visa purchase protections and a monthly FICO score estimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;earning-cash-back-rewards&quot;&gt;Earning cash back rewards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that this card has no annual fee, the rewards are pretty good. You can choose one of six categories for your 3% bonus category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online shopping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dining&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drug stores&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home improvement/furnishings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think that &lt;strong&gt;online shopping&lt;/strong&gt; is the best category. While using the card, we also found that online gift card purchases also count as online shopping. There were a few other surprising things that qualified for this category. Spending through the Kroger pay app available for use at Kroger stores, also counts towards the 3% bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maximizing-your-cash-back&quot;&gt;Maximizing your cash back&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have are enrolled in Bank of America’s preferred rewards program, you your cash back rate can increase by up to 75%. This means at the highest rate, you can receive up to 5.25% for your selected bonus category, 3.5% for groceries and gas, and 1.75% for all other spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-small-benefits&quot;&gt;Other small benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bank of America offers all it’s cardholder members &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.bankofamerica.com/en-us/what-guides-us/arts-and-culture/partners.html&quot;&gt;free admission&lt;/a&gt; to over 225 cultural institutions across the US during the first weekend of each month. Free admission includes authorized users as well, which can give your family free admission to a museum every month. Additionally, Bank of America offers BankAmericadeals, a program that offers you small extra savings in the form of statement credits for a variety of purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-the-boa-cash-rewards-card-for-you&quot;&gt;Is the BOA Cash Rewards card for you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are rather frugal with your spending, and have a large amount of assets (20k+) with either Bank of America or Merrill Edge, this card will help you save more money. Also, this card works extremely well when combined with other category-based cash back cards like the Discover it card and the Chase Freedom card, since it well compliments the categories of the two cards.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bank of America Cash Rewards Credit Card Review: A Supporting Player in Your Credit Card Strategy</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where can I buy good green tea?</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/12/28/where-can-you-buy-green-tea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where can I buy good green tea?" /><published>2019-12-28T17:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T17:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/12/28/where-can-you-buy-green-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/12/28/where-can-you-buy-green-tea.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-local-supermarket&quot;&gt;Your local supermarket&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most US Supermarkets carry some variety of green tea. You can often find it in some variety of it in the tea section, though it often won’t be imported. You can also often find the bottled honest tea at local stores such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.walmart.com/browse/honest-tea/YnJhbmQ6SG9uZXN0IFRlYQieie&quot;&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.target.com/b/honest-tea/-/N-551od&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, for about $1.79.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;japanese-green-tea&quot;&gt;Japanese Green Tea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kirklandtea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;costcos-kirkland-signature-green-tea-bags&quot;&gt;Costco’s Kirkland Signature Green Tea Bags&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.costco.com/kirkland-signature-green-tea-bags%2C-1.5-g%2C-100-count.product.100334938.html&quot;&gt;Costco’s Kirkland Signature Green Tea Bags&lt;/a&gt; which are produced by Ito-en in Japan have been consistently good for me. This one is my personal favorite, since it’s easily available, affordable and tastes just as Japanese green tea should. They come in packs of 100 for $15, which equates to about 15 cents a cup. The taste of the tea is slightly different than Ito-en’s bottled Oi Ocha or the Oi Ocha available in Japan, but it is nevertheless an enjoyable taste if you don’t let it oversteep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bottled-oi-ocha&quot;&gt;Bottled Oi Ocha&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Costco in the US has begun to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.costco.com/ito-en-oi-ocha-unsweetened-green-tea%2C-16.9-fl-oz%2C-12-count.product.100381540.html&quot;&gt;carry Oi ocha&lt;/a&gt; in certain states such as Colorado for about $16 / 12 pack. It is also regularly available on Amazon for about $15 / 12 pack, though the price often fluctuates. On Amazon, the 12-pack price can sometimes go down to $12 or about $1 a bottle. If you are not interested in buying this tea in packs of 12, or want to the tea soon, you can also find it at your local &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daisojapan.com/&quot;&gt;Daiso&lt;/a&gt; store, for about $1.75.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Your local supermarket Most US Supermarkets carry some variety of green tea. You can often find it in some variety of it in the tea section, though it often won’t be imported. You can also often find the bottled honest tea at local stores such as Walmart and Target, for about $1.79.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The top 8 health benefits of drinking green tea</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/12/28/health-benefits-of-green-tea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The top 8 health benefits of drinking green tea" /><published>2019-12-28T16:28:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T16:28:00-08:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/12/28/health-benefits-of-green-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/12/28/health-benefits-of-green-tea.html">&lt;p&gt;We consider green tea to be one of the healthiest things you can drink. Here are 8 positive effects of drinking Japanese green tea daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-green-tea-compounds-can-improve-your-brain-function&quot;&gt;1. Green tea compounds can improve your brain function&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like coffee, green tea contains caffeine, a stimulant which obviously makes our brain more alert. In addition, green tea contains Theanine which has been shown to have a positive impact on our mind can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hibiki-an.com/sp/contents.php/cnID/10&quot;&gt;improve our memory by&lt;/a&gt; increasing our dopamine levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-green-tea-improves-metabolism&quot;&gt;2. Green tea improves metabolism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green tea has been shown to improve your metabolism while being an excellent alternative to sugary drinks such as energy drinks and soda. The catechins in the green tea works to promote fat metabolism in the liver which improves metabolism. For more information about how green tea can help you lose weight, check out &lt;a href=&quot;/greentea/2019/07/12/can-green-tea-help-you-lose-weight.html&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-improving-heart-health&quot;&gt;3. Improving heart health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2006 Japanese &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16968850&quot;&gt;research study&lt;/a&gt; of more than 40500 participants found that adults who drank more than on average, five cups of tea daily were 26% less likely to die from a heart attack and stroke and overall 16% less likely do die from all causes of death. Besides losing weight, living longer is a pretty good benefits of drinking green tea, yeah?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-green-tea-may-help-prevent-cancer&quot;&gt;4. Green tea may help prevent cancer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green tea have catechins which work to help prevent cancer by inhibiting the growth of cancerous cells. EGCG contained in the tea may &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/diet/tea-fact-sheet&quot;&gt;protect cells from DNA damage&lt;/a&gt; caused by reactive oxygen species. There are other ways in which green tea consumption protects us against cancer such as activating enzymes that may help protect against tumor development and having polyphenols which inhibit tumor cell proliferation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-green-tea-lowers-your-risk-of-alzheimer-and-parkinsons&quot;&gt;5. Green tea lowers your risk of Alzheimer and Parkinsons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jbc.org/content/294/8/2714&quot;&gt;2019 study&lt;/a&gt; by USC researchers found that a diet containing compounds found in green tea and carrots reversed Alzheimer’s-like symptoms in mice. Green tea leaves contain  a compound called flavoids which can quell inflamation in arteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-green-tea-improves-your-teeth-and-dental-health&quot;&gt;6. Green tea improves your teeth and dental health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistently drinking green tea can protect us against cavities, gum disease and bad breath according to a 2016 study. This is because green tea bioflavonoids help &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deltadentalins.com/oral_health/tea.html&quot;&gt;kill and reduce harmful oral bacteria&lt;/a&gt; which lives in our mouths, thus protecting our dental health from these. Like protecting us against the other types of cancers, green tea can help prevent oral cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-green-tea-may-help-prevent-type-2-diabetes&quot;&gt;7. Green tea may help prevent type 2 diabetes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green tea lowers blood sugar levels through the polyphenols and polysaccharides contained in the tea leaves. Green tea polyphenols &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pacificcollege.edu/news/blog/2014/08/01/green-tea-lowers-blood-sugar-level&quot;&gt;help inhibit the amylase enzyme&lt;/a&gt; which the body uses to break down simple sugars, thus causing the body to absorb less of that sugar. And green tea may benefit diabetics as well because green tea catechins may reduce the glucose that passes through the intestine and into the blood stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-green-tea-may-help-reduce-heart-disease-and-stroke&quot;&gt;8. Green tea may help reduce heart disease and stroke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardiovascular diseases such as heart disease and stroke are dangerous to us, but green tea may help reduce the risk of these cardiovascular diseases. Green tea leaves contain a compound called flavoids which can quell inflamation in arteries and there’s also evidence that green tea can reduce the levels of unhealthy LDL cholestrol. Green tea is also shown to &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayAbstract?fromPage=online&amp;amp;aid=9371125&amp;amp;fileId=S0007114514001731&quot;&gt;reduce our blood pressure&lt;/a&gt;, though the effect is quite small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;healthiest-way-to-drink-green-tea&quot;&gt;Healthiest way to drink green tea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For maximum health benefit, we recommend drinking pure green tea without any milk or sugar, just like the Japanese have been doing for thousands of years. In addition, be careful to drink green tea in moderation. Drinking 100 cups of green tea a day is excessive and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.health.harvard.edu/heart-health/brewing-evidence-for-teas-heart-benefits&quot;&gt;likely harmful to you and your kidneys&lt;/a&gt;. But making it a habit to drink green tea daily can likely improve your health.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We consider green tea to be one of the healthiest things you can drink. Here are 8 positive effects of drinking Japanese green tea daily.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does green tea have caffeine?</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/15/does-green-tea-have-caffeine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does green tea have caffeine?" /><published>2019-07-15T13:28:41-07:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T16:28:00-08:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/15/does-green-tea-have-caffeine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/15/does-green-tea-have-caffeine.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sencha.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-green-tea-have-caffeine&quot;&gt;Does green tea have caffeine?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green tea indeed has caffeine but not as much as coffee of an equivalent serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-how-much&quot;&gt;But how much?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An 8-ounce cup of green tea can contain about &lt;a href=&quot;https://the.republicoftea.com/library/caffeine-in-tea/tea-and-caffeine/&quot;&gt;25mg~40mg of caffeine&lt;/a&gt;, and a 16oz / 500mL bottle of green tea would contains about 80mg. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://itoen.com/products/oi-ocha-green&quot;&gt;Oi-ocha&lt;/a&gt; bottled tea appears to contain 60mg per 500mL. In comparison, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.starbucks.com/menu/drinks/brewed-coffee/pike-place-roast&quot;&gt;Starbucks Grande-size (16oz)&lt;/a&gt; cup of coffee contains 310mg. So for any given volume, green tea caffeine has about five times as less caffeine content as a Grande-size Starbucks coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparing-caffeine-content&quot;&gt;Comparing caffeine content:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500mL (16oz) Oi Ocha: 60mg of caffeine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500mL (16oz) Starbucks coffee: 310mg of caffeine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;green-tea-with-less-caffeine&quot;&gt;Green tea with less caffeine?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can cold brew your green tea to reduce the caffeine content? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4648929/&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; suggests that brewing green tea cold can reduce caffeine content by about 10%. Sure, it may take longer than brewing green tea normally but you can brew tea to the same strength but with less caffeine. You simply have to take a tablespoon of tea leaves, a quart (1 litre) of water and throw it in the refrigerator for 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Jurokucha</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/14/what-is-jurokucha.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Jurokucha" /><published>2019-07-14T13:03:35-07:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T16:28:00-08:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/14/what-is-jurokucha</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/14/what-is-jurokucha.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jurokucha.jpg&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-jurokucha-tea&quot;&gt;What is Jurokucha tea?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jurokucha, literally “16 tea” gets its name from having 16 different ingredients which make up its base taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-inside&quot;&gt;What’s inside?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asahiinryo.co.jp/products/list/nutrition/0003.html&quot;&gt;Asahi website&lt;/a&gt;, the 16 ingredients that make up Jurokucha are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job’s tears, ハトムギ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;barley, 大麦&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;coffee weed, ハブ茶&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Germinating barley, 発芽大麦&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;brown rice, 玄米&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corn, とうもろこし&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loquat leaf, びわの葉&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;カワラケツメイ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Danilion root, たんぽぽの根&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green foxtail, あわ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proso millet, きび&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Azuki, 小豆&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perilla leaves, エゴマの葉&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Burdock, ごぼう&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jujube, ナツメ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tangerine peel, ミカンの皮
Or basically, a bit of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-popular-drink-in-japan&quot;&gt;A popular drink in Japan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After first being sold in 1993 16 tea became an instant success and is still a very popular tea to drink in Japan. Recently, Jurokucha has been started to be sold abroad as well and is quite popular in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16 tea has a slight sweetness, slightly roasted taste to it. It feels almost like a blend of oi-ocha with oksusu cha. It is widely available in Japan but not in the US. You might be able to find it in Asian grocery stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lived in Japan, I would typically drink two bottles of this tea every day since the tea itself was very easy to drink and doesn’t have caffeine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Can green tea help you lose weight?</title><link href="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/12/can-green-tea-help-you-lose-weight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can green tea help you lose weight?" /><published>2019-07-12T13:03:35-07:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T16:28:00-08:00</updated><id>https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/12/can-green-tea-help-you-lose-weight</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://teainsea.github.io/greentea/2019/07/12/can-green-tea-help-you-lose-weight.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sencha.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;can-green-tea-help-you-lose-weight&quot;&gt;Can green tea help you lose weight?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, multiple scientific studies have indeed proven that consistently drinking green tea can help you lose some weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tea-can-improve-metabolism&quot;&gt;Tea can improve metabolism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17299107/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; suggests that drinking tea increases metabolism by &lt;strong&gt;5%.&lt;/strong&gt; Green tea contains a plant compound called ECGC (Epigallocatechin gallate) at higher levels than other teas like black tea that boosts metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tea-can-help-you-consume-less-calories&quot;&gt;Tea can help you consume less calories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millions in Asian countries such as Japan and China drink cold unsweetened tea daily instead of sugary drinks. You can too. For instance, one that drinks 20oz of Coke (@210kcal) can replace their coke consumption with an unsweetened green tea, reducing their calorie consumption by &lt;strong&gt;1470 kcal weekly&lt;/strong&gt;. If one keeps this up for a year, they are on track to lose 26 pounds that they would have otherwise gained from the daily consumption of coke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weight-loss-teas-in-other-countries&quot;&gt;Weight loss teas in other countries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Japan’s Suntory has started selling a version of their popular Iemon tea, called the “Iemon tea special edition” (伊右衛門 特茶). Apparently, what makes it special are its claims to help with weight loss. It is not known whether the tea lives up to its claims where some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mynewsjapan.com/reports/1905&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; suggest that the tea has no real effect on weight loss. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.jp/%E3%83%88%E3%82%AF%E3%83%9B-%E3%82%B5%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC-%E4%BC%8A%E5%8F%B3%E8%A1%9B%E9%96%80-%E7%89%B9%E8%8C%B6-500ml%C3%9724%E6%9C%AC/product-reviews/B00EOI6XVY/&quot;&gt;Amazon reviews&lt;/a&gt; for this product are overall positive, but talk more about how the tea tastes good rather than actually helping them lose weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I myself has been drinking Suntory’s Black Oolong Tea (黒烏龍茶) for about one year, which is brewed to help with weight loss but I did not notice any change to my body weight or fat composition despite consistently drinking this product. Perhaps it could also be because most of the teas sold in Japan are already decently healthy so any improvements to health benefits of these products would be incremental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-can-tea-help-you-lose-weight&quot;&gt;So, can tea help you lose weight?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can conclude that tea can help with your weight loss, but the effect of tea may not be as big as you expect. Ultimately your weight loss depends on you, so your mileage my vary! Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>